

## IVY O'NEAL-ODOM

## Software Developer

#### Email:

ivyoo@protonmail.com

#### Address:

South Hadley, MA 01075

### **Resume in Brief**

A relentlessly curious software developer who likes to work both down at the metal and on the high level. Experience in both client and server-side development. A problem solver to the core, if it's challenging or interesting, it's getting done.

## **Experience**

#### **RESEARCH ASSISTANT**

Mount Holyoke College, South Hadley MA / December 2019 - Present

- Developed a cloud-based educational supplement for a 300-level Algorithms course at Mount Holyoke College.
- Researched effective teaching methods and implemented them in the above mentioned educational supplement.

## WEBSITE MANAGER

Mount Holyoke College, South Hadley MA / 2018 - Present

- Maintain and improve a public, dynamic website for the student organization Renegades.
- Manage a small team of server admins and community moderators for the student organization Renegades.

## FRONT END DEVELOPER AND ROBOTICIST

Enterra Solutions, Newtown PA / Summers of 2016 and 2015

- 2016 Designed and built a water filtration device and an associated cloud-based maintenance and diagnostic tools with a similar small team.
- 2015 Deployed a website which provided personalized vacation locations to users alongside a small team of fellow intern

## **Awards & Community**

#### HackHolyoke

(MLH) Runner-Up 2017

#### **AV Tech for TEDx**

George School 2016

## Compassionate Young Leaders Certificate

Dalai Lama Center for Ethics and Transformative Values at MIT 2016-2017

## Children's Hospital of Philadelphia

Member of Advisory Board 2016-2017

# Sustainable Architecture and Ecology Internship

Sirius Community 2019

## **Education**

### **Computer Science Major**

South Hadley, MA Graduation Date: May 2020

**GPA:** 3.58

### **Relevant Courses**

Compiler Design
Theory of Computation
Discrete Mathematics
Operating Systems
Artificial Intelligence
Modeling and Simulation
Physical Computing and
Robotics
Data Structures / Algorithms

## **Programming Languages**

Python

C / C++ / Arduino C Java / C#

RESTful APIs

Javascript / JQuery / Node.js